Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Records Documenting Swimming
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, records documenting swimming
1899-2013
RU 941
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
90.25
The records consist of correspondence, reports, scrapbooks, athlete files, photographs and publications documenting swimming at Yale.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Existence and Location of Copies
Swimming scrapbooks are available on microfilm from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM190. 1984. 4358 frames on 4 reels, 35mm.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Department of Athletics, 2005 and 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, reports, scrapbooks, athlete files, photographs and publications documenting swimming at Yale.
College sports; Swimming; Scrapbooks; Yale University Athletic Association; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Swimming; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics, Physical Education, and Recreation
- Scrapbooks of the swimming team, 1904-1936; Accession 2006-A-019
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1904-1923 (Box 1, Folder 1, Reel 1U)
    - 1907 (Box 1, Folder 2, Reel 1U)
    - 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 3, Reel 1U)
    - 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 4, Reel 1U)
    - 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 5, Reel 1U)
    - 1923-1925 (Box 3, Folder 6, Reel 1U)
    - 1926-1928, pt. 1 (Box 4, Folder 7, Reel 2U)
    - 1926-1928, pt. 2 (Box 5, Folder 8, Reel 2U)
    - 1928-1931, pt. 1 (Box 6, Folder 9, Reel 2U)
    - 1928-1931, pt. 2 (Box 7, Folder 10, Reel 2U)
    - 1930-1932 (Box 8, Folder 11 - 12, Reel 2U)
    - 1931-1934 (Box 9, Folder 13, Reel 3U)
    - 1932-1938 (Box 10, Folder 14-16, Reel 3U)
    - 1933 (Box 10, Folder 17, Reel 3U)
    - 1934-1936 (Box 11, Folder 18, Reel 4U)
- Scrapbooks of the swimming team, 1936-1957; Accession 2006-A-054
  Scope and Contents
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Scrapbooks, Oversize
    - 1936-1938 (Box 1, Reel 4U)
    - 1936-1950 (Box 2, Reel 4U)
    - 1939-1946 (Box 3, Reel 4U)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 4)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 5)
    - 1951-1955 (Box 6)
    - 1955-1957 (Box 7)
- Records documenting swimming, 1899-1995; Accession 2006-A-056
  Student and personnel records in boxes 13, folders 404-405 and box 14, folders 442-445 are restricted for 75 years from date of records as established by Yale Corporation regulations. Restriction dates are indicated at the file level.
  - AAU Administrative Files
    - Convention, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - National Office, 1953-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Connecticut Association, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Indoor AAU, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Other associations, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Indoor AAU, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - News bulletins, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Survey comm., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - National General, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - PEM-Conn.AAU, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Women's swimming, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - UNESCO, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Treasurer, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - YMCA relations, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Men's swimming, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 17 - 18)
    - Olympic development, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Travel expenses, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Advisory committee, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Gymnastics, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Executive/foreign relations, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Boxing, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - re: NCAA, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Sports governing, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Lawrence Johnson Award, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Constitutional by-laws regulations, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Association membership, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Connecticut, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Indoor AAU, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Connecticut AAU, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - AAU, Hainsworth/Lippman, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Confidential, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Cut-off times comm., Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Carnival
    - 34th annual, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - 35th annual, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - 36th annual, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - 37th annual, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - 38th annual, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - 39th annual, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - 40th annual, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - 41st annual, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - 42nd annual, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - 43rd annual, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - 44th annual, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - 45th annual, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - 46th annual, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - 47th annual, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - 48th annual, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 50 - 52)
    - 49th annual, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - 50th annual, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1950 (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - 1951 (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - 1952 (Box 3, Folder 57)
      - 1953 (Box 3, Folder 58)
      - 1954 (Box 3, Folder 59)
      - 1955 (Box 3, Folder 60)
      - 1956 (Box 3, Folder 61)
      - 1957 (Box 3, Folder 62)
      - 1958 (Box 3, Folder 63)
      - 1959 (Box 3, Folder 64)
      - WYBC, re: FM installation in gymnasium, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 65)
      - 1960 (Box 3, Folder 66 - 69)
      - 1961 (Box 3, Folder 70 - 71)
      - 1962 (Box 3, Folder 72 - 73)
      - 1963 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      - 1964 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      - 1965 (Box 3, Folder 76)
      - 1966 (Box 4, Folder 77)
      - 1967 (Box 4, Folder 78 - 79)
      - 1968 (Box 4, Folder 80)
      - 1969 (Box 4, Folder 81 - 82)
      - Stamford, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - 1970 (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - 1971 (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - 1972 (Box 4, Folder 87)
      - 1973 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Kiphuth, Ray
      - Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 89)
      - European trip-AAU Olympic committee, 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 90)
      - Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 91)
        - A-G, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 92)
        - H-P, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 93)
        - R-Z, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 94)
      - Miscellaneous, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 95)
      - Obertubessing-guides and almanacs and Yale souvenirs, 1942-1944 (Box 5, Folder 96)
      - A-F, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      - G-Z, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 98)
      - A-G, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 100)
      - H-M, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      - N-Z, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      - B-L, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      - M-W, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 104)
      - 1946 (Box 5, Folder 105)
      - 1948 (Box 5, Folder 106)
      - 1949 (Box 5, Folder 107)
      - A-D, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 108)
      - E-L, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 109)
      - M-R, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 110)
      - S-Y, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 111)
      - 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 112 - 114)
  - Kiphuth awards and certificates, 1912-1965 (Box 6)
  - Kiphuth awards and certificates, 1912-1965 (Box 37)
  - General administrative files
    - Miscellaneous, 1899-1920 (Box 7, Folder 119)
    - Awards-lists, 1920s-1930s (Box 7, Folder 120)
    - Yale personnel world records, 1934-1964 (Box 7, Folder 121)
    - Japan- trip/meet, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 122)
    - AAU report, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 123)
    - "New Haven Board of Recreation", 1947 (Box 7, Folder 124)
    - Job positions open in physical education, 1947-1951 (Box 7, Folder 125)
    - National Y.M.C.A, 1948-1952 (Box 7, Folder 126)
    - Pre-season, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - Why Yale?, circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 128)
    - Kiphuth biography, circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 129)
    - Body mechanics (Freshmen), circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 130)
    - Board of Control meetings, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 131)
    - Breaststroke, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 133)
    - Water filtration, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 134)
    - AAU Olympic committee, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 135)
    - Connecticut AAU, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - Foreign letters, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - General correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 138 - 155)
    - U.S. Olympic association, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - History of Yale swimming season, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - Red Cross, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Australia swimming correspondence, 1951-1963 (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - AAU letters received abroad, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - Boy Scouts of America, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - Cancer research, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Resolution to support broad aquatic programme, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - New Haven Y.M.C.A. physical education, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - AAU letters, 1952-1952 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Kiphuth engagements, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Limited editions club, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Recommendations, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - AAU, 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - Prospects, 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Moriarty miscellaneous, 1952-1956 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Moriarty miscellaneous, 1953-1958 (Box 8, Folder 177 - 182)
    - Fort Lauderdale Forum, 1953-1955 (Box 8, Folder 183)
    - Faculty swimming, 1953-1958 (Box 8, Folder 185)
    - Letters of recommendation, 1953-1959 (Box 8, Folder 189)
    - New Haven Swim Club, 1953-1963 (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - Swimming budget forms, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 192)
    - C.N.C.A. Conference, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 193)
    - France correspondence, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - Practice by boys other than Yale personnel, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 195)
    - Diving, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 196)
    - Freshman swimming correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 197)
    - Varsity swimming correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Swimming pools: sanitation, construction, equipment, etc., 1954-1956 (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - AAU Convention, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Christmas swimming, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - C.N.C.A., 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 202 - 203)
    - C.N.C.A. Conference, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 204 - 205)
    - E.I.S.L. Coaches Association, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - New Zealand swimming correspondence, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - AAU Connecticut assn., 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - AAU rules changes, 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - C.N.C.A. "Training the Diving Judge", 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - C.N.C.A. correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 211)
    - Moriarty India trip, 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - N.C.A.A. minutes of meetings, 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - Poland swimming correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - E.I.S.L. Swimming Coaches Assn., 1955-1957 (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - Hopping Award, 1955-1958 (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - Yale A.A. memos, 1955-1959 (Box 9, Folder 217)
    - Health, Dept. of Univ., 1955-1959 (Box 9, Folder 218)
    - Miscellaneous, 1955-1960 (Box 9, Folder 219 - 228)
    - Service bureau, 1955-1959 (Box 9, Folder 229)
    - Soccer, 1955-1959 (Box 9, Folder 230)
    - Telephone and telegraph, 1955-1959 (Box 9, Folder 231)
    - C.N.C.A. conference, 1955-1960 (Box 9, Folder 232)
    - Germany swimming correspondence, 1955-1960 (Box 9, Folder 233)
    - Hungary swimming correspondence, 1955-1962 (Box 9, Folder 235)
    - Japan swimming correspondence, 1955-1964 (Box 9, Folder 236)
    - All-American lists, 1955-1967 (Box 9, Folder 237)
    - C.N.C.A. conference registration, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 238)
    - Christmas recess swimming, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 239)
    - Olympic training at Yale, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 240)
    - South America swimming correspondence, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 241)
    - Spain swimming correspondence, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 242)
    - Mixed results, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 243)
    - Freshman correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box 10, Folder 244 - 245)
    - Gymnasium (re: thefts), 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 246)
    - Romanian aquatics tour, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 248)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956-1959 (Box 10, Folder 250 - 255)
    - Swimming budgets, 1956-1960 (Box 10, Folder 256)
    - Correspondence with Yale Administration, 1956-1962 (Box 10, Folder 257)
    - Swimming Advisory Committee, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 258)
    - Christmas swimming, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 259)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1965 (Box 10, Folder 260 - 261)
    - Hungarian relief meet, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 262)
    - Summer training programme, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 263)
    - C.N.C.A., 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 264 - 265)
    - General warning, 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 266)
    - Inquiries, 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 268)
    - Interpretations, 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 269)
    - Varsity correspondence and results, 1957-1959 (Box 10, Folder 273)
    - C.N.C.A. Conference, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 274)
    - National Collegiate, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 275)
    - "The Golden Book of the International Swimming Sport", 1958 (Box 10, Folder 276)
    - Hungarian Swimming Association, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 277)
    - NCAAs, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 279)
    - NCAA rules changes, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 280)
    - South Africa, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 281)
    - Summer training programme, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 282)
    - Swim team budget, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 283)
    - C.N.C.A. (diving film), 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 284)
    - Staff correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 285)
    - School of Engineering, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 286)
    - Service bureau, 1958-1961 (Box 10, Folder 287)
    - Summer jobs, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 288)
    - England correspondence, 1958-1961 (Box 10, Folder 289)
    - Advice, requests for, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 290)
    - Breaststroke, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 292)
    - India correspondence, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 294)
    - Mexico correspondence, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 296)
    - Summer training programme, 1959-1963 (Box 11, Folder 297 - 301)
    - YMCA (national), 1959 (Box 11, Folder 302)
    - Y.S.A. luncheons, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 303 - 304)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1959-1964 (Box 11, Folder 306 - 313)
    - Press, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 315)
    - Yale Naval ROTC Unit, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 316)
    - Yale A.A. correspondence, 1959-1965 (Box 11, Folder 317 - 318)
    - F.I.no date, 1959-1962 (Box 11, Folder 320)
    - AAU award, 1959-1962 (Box 11, Folder 321)
    - Contacts, circa 1960 (Box 11, Folder 322)
    - C.N.C.A., 1960 (Box 11, Folder 323)
    - Officials, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 324)
    - Olympic coaching job, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 325)
    - Physical training, 1960s (Box 11, Folder 326)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 327 - 328)
    - Freshman correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 329)
    - E.C.A.C., 1961 (Box 11, Folder 330)
    - Payne Whitney Gym report, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 332)
    - Yale College, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 333)
    - Camera, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 334)
    - NCAA Championships, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 335)
    - Scoreboard, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 336)
    - Coaches associations, 1962-1967 (Box 11, Folder 337)
    - Exercises, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 338)
    - NCAAs, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 339)
    - YMCA executive meeting minutes, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 340)
    - Gymnasium annual reports, 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 341)
    - Community school and recreation, 1963-1965 (Box 12, Folder 343)
    - American Swimming Coaches Association Newsletter, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 344)
    - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 345)
    - Paperwork information, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 346)
    - Resumes and recommendations, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 347)
    - Summer swimming, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 348)
    - Athletic Department miscellaneous, 1964-1970 (Box 12, Folder 349)
    - Rosters, 1964-1970 (Box 12, Folder 350)
    - AAU Outdoor Championships, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 351)
    - AAU mailing list, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 352)
    - All American lists, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 353)
    - College Swimming Association of America, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 354)
    - Exhibition Pool, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 356)
    - Mexico correspondence, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 360)
    - Mexico Trip By R.K., 1966 (Box 12, Folder 361)
    - Peace Corps, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 362)
    - Miscellaneous committees and associations, 1966-1969 (Box 12, Folder 363)
    - Miscellaneous Ivy League, 1966-1970 (Box 12, Folder 364)
    - ESIS-EISL, 1966-1972 (Box 12, Folder 365)
    - New Haven Swim Club, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 366)
    - Indication, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 368)
    - Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 369)
    - Yale Swimming Association records, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 370)
    - Calhoun College (Fellows), 1967-1970 (Box 12, Folder 371)
    - Electronic timer, 1967-1970 (Box 12, Folder 372)
    - Yale Swimming Association, 1967-1972 (Box 12, Folder 373)
    - Kiphuth biography, circa 1968 (Box 12, Folder 374)
    - Personal bests, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 375)
    - IOC newsletters, -1968 (Box 12, Folder 376)
    - AAU memo, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 377)
    - All-American team, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 378)
    - Swimming Hall of Fame, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 379)
    - Connecticut AAU, 1968-1971 (Box 12, Folder 380)
    - Books, 1968-1971 (Box 12, Folder 381)
    - AAU Championships, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 382)
    - Belgian trip, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 383)
    - Coaches Committee, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 384)
    - Ft. Lauderdale Forum, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 385)
    - Swimming records, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 387)
    - Timer clock, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 388)
    - Freshman rosters, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 389)
    - Gymnasium-fitness, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 390)
    - Staff-memos, 1969-1972 (Box 12, Folder 392)
    - Admissions, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 393)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 394)
    - St. Louis Country Club, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 395)
    - Workouts, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 396)
    - Budget, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 397 - 399)
    - C.N.C.A., 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 400)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 401)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 402)
    - Pan Am Games, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 403)
    - Accident reports, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 404)
      Accident reports are restricted until January 1, 2048 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - Admissions and letters, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 405)
      Admissions materials are restricted until January 1, 2048 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - College Swimming Coaches Association of America, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 406)
    - Eastern Championships, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 407)
    - Florida fund raising, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 408)
    - Florida trip, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 409)
    - Harvard swimming, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 410)
    - Roster, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 411)
    - Summer newsletter, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 412)
    - Workouts, 1972-1974 (Box 13, Folder 413 - 414)
    - AAU Conn. Association, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 415)
    - C.N.C.A., 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 416)
    - Newsletter, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 417 - 418)
    - Winter training camp, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 419)
    - H.S. relays, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 421)
    - Rule change proposal, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 422)
    - Swimming applicants, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 423)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 424 - 425)
    - Body mechanics, undated (Box 13, Folder 426)
    - Diving, undated (Box 13, Folder 427)
    - Diving judges cards, undated (Box 13, Folder 428)
    - Films- loaned out, undated (Box 13, Folder 429)
    - Origin of crawl (stroke), undated (Box 13, Folder 430)
    - Yale fitness survey, undated (Box 13, Folder 431)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 13, Folder 432)
    - Swim coordinator (Full Time), 1980 (Box 14, Folder 433)
    - Swim coordinator (Part Time), 1980 (Box 14, Folder 434)
    - Swimming (Women), 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 435)
    - Swimming (Men), 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 436)
    - Men's swimming post season, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 437)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 14, Folder 439)
    - Kiphuth Fellow, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 440)
    - Swimming Sol. letter, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 441)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 444)
      File is restricted until January 1, 2062 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - Swimming phonathon, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 446)
    - Budget (W), 1986 (Box 14, Folder 447)
    - Sport Org. (W), 1986 (Box 14, Folder 448)
    - Z (W), 1986 (Box 14, Folder 449)
    - Budget (M), 1986 (Box 14, Folder 450)
    - Schedule (M), 1986 (Box 14, Folder 451)
    - Sport Org. (M), 1986 (Box 14, Folder 452)
    - Z (M), 1986 (Box 14, Folder 453)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 454)
    - Women's swimming, 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 455)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 456)
    - Yale Swimming Association, 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 457)
    - Swimming phonathon thank you letter #2, 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 458)
    - "Hazelwood Plan", 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 459)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 460)
    - Letters and memos, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 461)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 462)
    - Australia, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 463)
    - Swim newsletter, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 464)
    - (m/w), 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 465)
    - Swimming, 1989-1991 (Box 14, Folder 466)
    - Roster, 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 467)
  - Olympics
    - 1928 (Box 15, Folder 468)
    - 1936 (Box 15, Folder 469)
    - Tokyo/Helsinki, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 470)
    - US Olympic committee, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 471)
    - Tryouts, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 472)
    - Olympic Association, 1947- 1948 (Box 15, Folder 473)
    - Olympic Games, London, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 474)
    - Men's swimming committee, 1949-1952 (Box 15, Folder 475)
    - Helsinki, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 476)
    - Helsinki Presse, circa 1951 (Box 15, Folder 477)
    - Bureau Agenda Helsinki, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 478)
    - Pan American Games, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 479)
    - "Olympic Committee", 1952 (Box 15, Folder 480)
    - Olympic committee correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 15, Folder 481 - 482)
    - Olympic Games, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 483)
    - XV Olympia Helsinki Presse, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 484)
    - Olympic trials, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 486)
    - Olympic Games, Melbourne, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 487 - 488)
    - Olympic games and tryouts, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 489 - 490)
    - Olympic Games, Rome, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 491)
    - Report on IOC meeting in Athens, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 492)
    - USOC reports/newsletters, 1961-1963 (Box 15, Folder 493)
    - USOC, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 494)
    - Olympic tryouts, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 495)
    - Olympic Games, Tokyo, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 496 - 498)
    - Olympic committee, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 499)
    - Bulgarian Olympic committee bulletin, 1966- 1968 (Box 16, Folder 500)
    - USOC, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 501)
    - IOC newsletter, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 502)
    - Olympics, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 503)
    - Munich, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 504)
    - No Date (Box 16, Folder 505 - 506)
    - General
      - 1930s (Box 38)
      - 1950s (Box 38)
      - 1960s (Box 38)
    - 1972 championships (Box 39)
    - Olympic committee programs, 1924, 1940, 1948 (Box 39)
    - Kiphuth photographs, 1972 (Box 39)
    - Olympic semi-centennial dinner, 1946 (Box 39)
    - 1968 Olympic trials (Box 39)
    - US Olympic committee, 1950, 1958 (Box 39)
  - Photographs
    - Japanese swimmers, undated (Box 17, Folder 507 - 508)
    - Signed photographs, undated (Box 17, Folder 509)
    - Unsigned Photographs
      - no date (Box 18, Folder 510 - 513)